Register of the Nikolai Ustrialov Papers, 1920-1935
Hoover Institution Archives
Nikolai Ustrialov Papers,
1920-1935
XX179
Ustrialov, N. (Nikolaĭ)
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence and writings, relating to the Russian Revolution, the White governments in Omsk, 1918-1919, and eurasianism.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (1 reel).
Access Points
Eurasian movement; Soviet Union; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921
Biographical Note
1890 Born, Russia Receives law degree from Moscow University Teaches at Moscow and Perm' Universities
1917 Joins Konstitutsionno-Demokraticheskaia Partiia (Kadets). During Civil War works in propaganda department of Admiral Kolchak's government. Is involved in the publication of Utro Rossii, Russkaia Mysl' and Russkoe Delo
1921 Emigrates to Harbin, China. Joins "Smenovekhovtsvo Movement". Publishes in Smena Vek, Nakanune, and Novosti ZHizni
1920's Serves as library director in Soviet administration of the Chinese Eastern Railroad in Manchuria
1930-1935 Teaches at Harbin University
1935 Returns to the Soviet Union. Teaches at the Institute of Transportation Engineers in Moscow
1938 Dies
Series Description
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE, 1920-1935. (Box 1)
  Typescript copies of Nikolai Ustrialov's correspondence, compiled by him in Harbin, China, between 1934 and 1935. Some of Ustrialov's personal letters have been edited by him for this typescript version. He has also included short introductions to each section of the correspondence as well as excerpts from his diaries. Arranged alphabetically by political affiliation of correspondent or name of correspondent
- WRITINGS, 1935. (Box 1)
  Typescript draft of "Belyi Omsk"
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE, 1920-1935
  - General
    - Miscellaneous. Includes short biographical sketches of correspondents: Lev Zander, 1920-1921; Vsevolod Ivanov, 1920-1922; Princess Liubov' Golitsyna, 1920-1922; H. Bourrier, 1921; F. Kubka, 1921-1930; P. IAkovlev; Georgii Tel'berg, 1921; Baron IUrii Disterlo, 1921; Aleksandr Bonch-Osmolovskii, 1922; IAkovlev-Dunin, 1921; IUrii Markhlevskii, 1922; Artemii Savitskii, 1922; Prince Nikolai Ukhtomskii, 1923-1924; A. Kaun, 1923; G. Manns, 1923; Nikolai Smirnov, 1924; Sergei Sverzhenskii, 1924; Mikhail Pergament, 1925-1926; I. Geintsman, 1925; N. Rusov, 1925; Boris Pil'niak, 1926; Sergei Rostislavov, 1926; IUliia Tripolitova; Kurachi, 1926; Nikolai TSurikov, 1926-1927; N. Smirnov; Ol'ga CHichagova, 1927-1929; Georgii Gins, 1928-1930; El'pidifor Titov, 1929; Amplii Avdoshchenkov, 1929; Evgenii IAshnov, 1929-1934; Efim CHepurkovskii, 1930; A. Kotel'nikov, 1930-1934; L. Bykhovskii, 1931; Vasilii Alekseev, 1931-1933; S. Dmitrievskii, 1932-1933; Vladimir Lamanskii, 1933-1934; "Skitalets", 1934 (Box 1., Folder 1-6)
    - "Porevoliutsionery". Includes Nikolai Bylov, 1928; N. Alekseev, 1931; Porevoliutsionnyi Klub, 1933; IUrii SHirinskii-SHikhmatov, 1933-1935; N. Perfil'ev, 1935 (Folder 7-8)
    - "Smenovekhovtsy". Includes IUrii Kliuchnikov, 1919-1926; IUrii Potekhin, 1921-1923; Aleksandr Bobrishchev-Pushkin, 1922-1923; Sergei Luk'ianov, 1922-1931; Nikolai Alekseev, 1922; N. R., 1923; Aleksandr Zarudnyi, 1925 (Folder 9-12)
  - Dikii, Grigorii, 1927-1934 (Folder 13-17)
  - Lezhnev, Isai, 1923-1926 (Folder 18)
  - Suvchinskii, Petr, 1926-1930 (Folder 19)
- WRITINGS, 1935.
  - "Belyi Omsk". Typescript copy (Box 1., Folder 20-23)